Gothenburg, Sweden +46709637400 junsheng.fu@zenuity.com

# Junsheng Fu

<u>GitHub</u> <u>Patents</u> <u>Homepage</u>

I am a Senior Algorithm Engineer and Computer Vision Researcher with 8 patents, 5 publications and 13 open source projects in the filed of autonomous driving and computer vision. I am experienced with both academic research and industry innovations, familiar with lidar/radar/street-view data processing, and have 4-year experience as a Computer Vision Researcher working with commercial HD map data in Nokia Research.

## **Technical skills**

Languages: Python, Matlab, C/C++

Frameworks: TensorFlow, Keras, CUDA, OpenCV, Scikit-learn,

Others: Camera pose estimation, Deep Learning, Tracking, SLAM, Git, Linux

## **Projects**

Real-time Vehicle Localization with a Particle Filter	Demo
Object Tracking with Extended Kalman Filter	Demo
Real-time Vehicle Detection with Deep Neural Network	Demo
Monocular Camera-based Lane Departure Warning	<u>Demo</u>
Use a Convolutional Neural Network to Drive a Car in Game Simulator	Demo
Object Tracking with Unscented Kalman Filter	<u>Demo</u>
Autonomous Driving with Model Predictive Control	<u>Demo</u>
Traffic Sign Recognition with Neural Network	<u>Demo</u>
Traffic Light Detection and Classification with Deep Neural Network	<u>Demo</u>
Drivable Road Semantic Segmentation with Fully Convolutional Network	<u>Demo</u>
Autonomous Driving with PID Controller	<u>Demo</u>
Highway Multi-lanes Path Planning in a Game Simulator	<u>Demo</u>
6-DoF Camera Pose Estimation with 3D Point Cloud	Demo

#### **Experience**

Zenuity Senior Algorithm Engineer Sweden | 1.2018-now

 Working on algorithm research and development for robust localization and perception for autonomous vehicles in variations of environmental and weather conditions.

Tampere University of Technology Doctoral Student Finland | 1.2014-1.2018

- Implemented 13 autonomous driving demos with OpenCV, Python, Keras, and TensorFlow (videos).
- Working on camera pose estimation with LIDAR and street-view data.
- Served as teaching Assistant for "SGN-13006 Introduction to Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning", and got the best course reviews award from students in 2016 Fall Semester.

Nokia Research (Nokia Tech) Computer Vision Researcher Finland | 3.2012-12.2015

- Designed and implemented a 3D Map Augmented Photo gallery application with **HERE** Map (<u>video</u>).
- Developed an Interactive Video Playback System with HERE Map (video).
- Implemented 3D reconstruction and visualization systems for indoor 3D smart sensing.

Tampere University of Technology Research Assistant Finland | 9.2010-12.2011

- Designed and implemented a real-time video denoising filter with C.
- Embedded a denoising filter into H.264/AVC codecs.

Demola Software Engineer Finland | 3.2010-8.2010

Implemented a face tracking application in Nokia N900 mobile phone with OpenCV and QT.

#### Education

Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Computer Vision, Ph.D.	GPA: 4.83 / 5	2018
Tampere University of Technology, Finland - Signal Processing, M.Sc.	GPA: 4.45 / 5	2012
Hangzhou Dianzi University, China - Telecommunication, B.Eng.	GPA: 85 / 100	2009
Udacity - Self-Driving-Car Engineer Nanodegree		2018

#### **Patents & Publications**

- US20170132843A1, A Method and Technical Equipment for Determining a Pose of a Device, published 2017 (link).
- US 20160248985, Device with an Adaptive Camera Array, published 2016 (link).
- WO 2016102768 A1, Monitoring, published 2016 (link)
- EP 3051410 A1, An apparatus and associated methods for provision of wireless power, published 2016 (link)
- US 20160191796, Methods And Apparatuses For Directional View In Panoramic Content, published 2016 (link)
- US 20150155009, Method And Apparatus For Media Capture Device Position Estimate- Assisted Splicing Of Media, published 2015 (link)
- US 20140300775, Method and Apparatus for Determining Camera Location Information and/or Camera Pose Information According to a Global Coordinate System, published 2016 (link)
- US 20150109508, Method And Apparatus For Generating A Media Capture Request Using Camera Pose Information, published 2015 (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, K. Roimela, Y. You, and V.-V. Mattila: "A 3d Map Augmented Photo Gallery Application on Mobile Device", IEEE ICIP 2014, France (link)
- J. Fu, J.-K. Kämäräinen, A. Buch, and N. Krüger: "Indoor Objects and Outdoor Urban Scenes Recognition by 3D Visual Primitives", ACCV workshop 2014, Singapore (link)
- J. Fu, L. Fan, Y. You, and K. Roimela: "Augmented and Interactive Video Playback Based on Global Camera Pose", the 21st ACM Multimedia, 2013, Spain (<u>link</u>).
- L. Fan, J. Fu, Y. You, K. Roimela, P. Piippo and V.-V. Mattila, "Deja Vu: A 3D map augmented photo gallery application on mobile devices", In IEEE ICCV 2013, Demo session, Australia.
- J. Fu, E. Belyaev and K. Egiazarian: "Rate-distortion Oriented Joint Video Pre-filtering and Compression", the 10th conference of FRUCT, 2011, Finland (<u>link</u>).
- Junsheng Fu, Master Thesis 2011: A Real-Time Rate-Distortion Oriented Join Video Denoising and Compression Algorithm (<u>link</u>).

## **Honors and Activities**

TUT Graduate School Scholarship	2016-2017
Nokia Foundation Scholarship	2014
<ul> <li>Sisu Award, Nokia Research Center Multimedia Technology Lab</li> </ul>	2013
Runner-up in IIDA Idea Innovation Competition	2011
Outstanding Graduate Award	2009
<ul> <li>Chairman of Tampere Chinese Student and Scholar Association</li> </ul>	2014-2015
Chairman of one Badminton Club in Tampere	2012